Guide to the Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers
The Lewis Walpole Library
Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers
1800-1980
1926-1979
LWL MSS 20
The Lewis Walpole Library
169.07
355 boxes + 5 broadsides
The Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers consists of correspondence, writings, financial records, and other papers documenting the personal and professional activities and interests of the American author, editor, and collector Wilmarth Lewis and his wife Annie Burr Lewis. At their home in Farmington, Connecticut, the Lewises created a world-renowned collection of eighteenth-century print, graphic, and manuscript material related to the English author, connoisseur, and collector Horace Walpole (1717-1797), and his circle. Lewis's papers are predominantly related to his work on Walpole, his involvement with organizations including Yale University, the Thacher School, Historic Deerfield, and the National Portrait Gallery, and the Lewises' social and intellectual lives in England, New England, and Washington, D.C.
Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979
Kilby, Clyde S., 1902-1986
Roach, Marilynne K., 1946-
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Boxes 183-185: Restricted. For further information consult the director.
Boxes 343-355: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the director.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis (Yale 1918), 1979.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1901-1979. II. Service and Affiliations, 1931-1979. III. Writings, 1915-1980. IV. Personal Papers, 1800-1980. V. Subject Files, 1903-1979. VI. Real Estate Records, 1926-1980. VII. Financial Records, 1926-1980.
Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis (1895-1979)
Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis was born in Alameda, California, on November 14, 1895, the son of Miranda Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis and Azro Nathaniel Lewis. He attended the Thacher School in Ojai, California, and Yale University (Class of 1918). He met Annie Burr Auchincloss (1902-1959) in Farmington, Connecticut, in 1923, and the couple were married in 1928. Together they spent three decades building a collection of books, prints, paintings, manuscripts, and decorative arts related to Horace Walpole, his circle, and his time, and formed a research library at their home in Farmington. Wilmarth Lewis died in Hartford on October 7, 1979; he left his home and collections to Yale University by bequest.
Annie Burr Lewis (1902-1959)
Annie Burr Auchincloss Lewis was born in Newport, Rhode Island, on July 22, 1902, the daughter of Emma Jennings Auchincloss and Hugh Dudley Auchincloss. She attended Miss Porter's School in Farmington, Connecticut, and married Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis (1895-1979) in New York in 1928. The Lewises resided in Farmington and at Hammersmith Farm in Newport. Annie Lewis died in Hartford, Connecticut, on May 9, 1959.
Related Materials
Associated material: Annie Burr Lewis and Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Photographs (LWL MSS 22), The Lewis Walpole Library.
Associated material: Yale Edition of Horace Walpole's Correspondence Editorial Project Records (LWL MSS 23), The Lewis Walpole Library.
Scope and Contents
The Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers consists of correspondence, writings, financial records, and other papers documenting the personal and professional activities and interests of the American author, editor, and collector Wilmarth Lewis and his wife Annie Burr Lewis. At their home in Farmington, Connecticut, the Lewises created a world-renowned collection of eighteenth-century print, graphic, and manuscript material related to the English author, connoisseur, and collector Horace Walpole (1717-1797), and his circle. Most of Lewis's papers are related to his work on Walpole, his involvement with organizations including Yale University, the Thacher School, Historic Deerfield, and the National Portrait Gallery, and to the Lewises' social and intellectual lives in England, New England, and Washington, D.C.
Lewis's correspondence files comprise over half of the papers. Like Horace Walpole, Lewis built a network of colleagues and friends over his lifetime, making connections based on his interests and travels. His network was begun when he enrolled at the Thacher School in Ojai, California, and expanded greatly when he moved on to Yale University in 1914. The friends he made at Yale stayed with him for life as borne out through the correspondence files: many of the over 2,000 names listed are notable figures in twentieth-century culture as leaders in the arts, education, literature, government, business, and medicine, and a good subset of those were classmates in New Haven. To hundreds of others Lewis wrote looking for information or Walpole material, or advice on a Walpole matter, and scholars wrote to him for the same cause. He was loyal to many organizations, and the files document how he gave his time and expertise as a trustee and select committee member at his two schools, as well as to museums, libraries, and historical organizations stretching from Newport to Washington, and out to California.
As an author, Lewis was prolific, turning out dozens of essays, chapters, and books on Horace Walpole over a forty-year period, all while he was overseeing the final production of all but the last two volumes of the Yale Edition of Horace Walpole's Correspondence. A popular speaker, he regularly gave academic, commencement, after-dinner, and library lectures; the files document well over one hundred presentations, many of which were published afterward. Lewis was awarded eleven honorary degrees between 1937 and 1972, from universities in the United States, Ireland, England, and Australia, in addition to several medals for service and accomplishments from American universities, clubs, and the Royal Society of Arts. His eight scrapbooks and folders of clippings cover well the publicity he garnered for his honors earned, appearances made, and publications issued between 1932 and 1978. The collection ends with documentation of Wilmarth and Annie Lewis's homes in Farmington, Newport, and Washington, D.C., the guests who enjoyed their gracious hospitality, and the finances that underwrote their life and adventures together.
In a December 23, 1963, letter to his colleagues Julian P. Boyd and Catherine Drinker Bowen, serving with him on the National Portrait Gallery Commission, Lewis wrote, "Isn't it delightful being Doorkeepers to Posterity?" The Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers present evidence of a remarkable man, a doorkeeper who led a life of collecting books, manuscripts, art, information, honors, and friends in service to eighteenth-century scholarship and to his chosen communities.
Separated Materials
Printed material found within the collection was removed for separate cataloging and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
Authors; Bibliographers; Book editors; Collectors and collecting; Financial records; Scrapbooks; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968; Bacon, Leonard, 1887-1954; Bennett, Charles H. (Charles Hodges), 1906-; Benson, John Howard, 1901-1956; Bentley, R. (Richard), 1854-1936; Boyd, Julian P. (Julian Parks), 1903-1980; Burke, Joseph, 1913-1992; Carter, John, 1905-1975; Chapman, R. W. (Robert William), 1881-1960; Coombe, Reginald G.; Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960; Fitts, Clive Hamilton, 1900-1984; Flandrau, Grace, 1889-1971; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Fulton, John F. (John Farquhar), 1899-1960; Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stevenson), 1890-1972; Gibson, Langhorne, 1899-; Hazen, Allen T. (Allen Tracy), 1904-1977; Hill, Draper; Hudson, Elizabeth; Hyde, Donald Frizell, 1909-1966; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Ketton-Cremer, R. W. (Robert Wyndham), 1906-1969; Kilby, Clyde S., 1902-1986; Kimball, Richard A.; Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1892-1973; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984; Knopf, Blanche W., 1894-1966; Lam, George L. (George Lorant), 1909-1970; Lamont, Thomas Stilwell, 1899-1967; Leonard, Joseph, 1877-1964; Lewis, Annie Burr Auchincloss, 1902-1959; Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979; Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979; McCarthy, Michael J., 1939-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Metcalfe, K. M. (Katherine Marion); Metzdorf, Robert F. (Robert Frederic), 1912-; Munby, A. N. L. (Alan Noel Latimer), 1913-1974; Namier, L. B. (Lewis Bernstein), 1888-1960; Olds, Irving S. (Irving Sands), 1887-1963; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994; Osborn, James M. (James Marshall), 1906-1976; Pottle, Frederick A. (Frederick Albert), 1897-1987; Richardson, E. P. (Edgar Preston), 1902-1985; Ripley, S. Dillon (Sidney Dillon), 1913-2001; Roach, Marilynne K., 1946-; Roberts, S. C. (Sydney Castle), 1887-1966; Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt, 1861-1933; Sassoon, Sybil, 1894-1989; Shortall, Harrington, 1895-1984; Smith, Warren Hunting, 1905-1998; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963; Wallace, A. Dayle (Alva Dayle), 1908-1973; Walpole, Horace, 1717-1797; Whibley, Leonard, 1862 or 1863-1941; Whitridge, Arnold, 1891-1989; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Alfred A. Knopf, Inc; Heritage Foundation (Deerfield, Mass.); Miss Porter's School (Farmington, Conn.); National Portrait Gallery (Smithsonian Institution); Thacher School (Ojai, Calif.); Yale Corporation; Yale University; Yale University. Library
- Correspondence, 1901–1979; Series I; 76.56; 181 boxes
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into five subseries: General Correspondence, Chapman-Lewis-Whibley Correspondence, Lewis Family Correspondence, Responses to Publications, and Tributes and Condolences.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains Wilmarth Lewis's extensive collection of letters from and to more than two thousand colleagues, friends, and family members. The breadth and depth of the collection is what distinguishes it: Lewis's personal life and professional work were largely united and this fact is reflected in both the contents and the correspondents found here. Because he had secretarial help for most of his adult life, the files frequently hold two-way correspondence composed of incoming letters and the typed carbon copies of Lewis's replies. In other cases, letters were returned to the Lewis Walpole Library by their recipients, and those accessions and donors are noted at the folder level.
  The first subseries, General Correspondence, spanning sixty-four linear feet and sixty-five years, is the bulk of the series. The letters are a mix of social and scholarly content, often within the same folder, and are international in scope though predominantly from friends and colleagues in the United States and the United Kingdom. Lewis's ongoing research on Horace Walpole is the theme of many letters, as is the building of his collection of books, manuscripts, prints, paintings, and objects related to Walpole and his circle. Over many years Lewis built—and mined—a great network of academics, authors, collectors, dealers, and librarians who helped him achieve his pursuits, and the correspondents come from the spectrum within those professions. Eminent faculty from Yale, Oxford, and Cambridge universities, prominent library and museum directors in England and America, renowned international antiquarian booksellers, and legendary editors and publishers appear throughout the files, and their names stand out in the folder list. Also present, however, are legions of English country house residents and their descendants, bibliographers, fact-checkers, and other less-recognized foot soldiers of history. Among that cohort is A. John Watson, a manuscript librarian at the British Museum who met Lewis in 1933, and continued to assist with his Walpole research for many years after his retirement from the museum in 1952. The two corresponded for forty-five years, and in 1983 Watson, at age 93, mailed to Farmington the letters he had received from Lewis; most had been hand-written so carbons were not present in the files, and the letters were added in with those from Watson to Lewis.
  A special category of correspondents in the subseries is the staff of the Yale Edition of Horace Walpole's Correspondence Project (the records of which are described separately under the call number LWL MSS 23). The correspondence span dates after their names reveal the decades of dedicated service given to Lewis, their editor in chief, by the workers in "The Factory" at Yale's Sterling Memorial Library: Charles H. Bennett (1937-1957), Ralph S. Brown Jr. (1936-1976), Grover Cronin (1946-1960), Andrew G. Hoover (1936-1953), George L. Lam (1937-1979), Edwine M. Martz (1942-1979), Robert A. Smith (1949-1968), Warren Hunting Smith (1935-1979), and A. Dayle Wallace (1933-1973). Similarly, correspondence with members of the Advisory Board, including Edgar S. Furniss (1934-1967), Andrew Keogh (1931-1951), R. W. Ketton-Cremer (1931-1970), O. F. Morshead (1932-1977), L. B. Namier (1933-1971), Frederick A. Pottle (1927-1979), Chauncey Brewster Tinker (1923-1963), and Earl Waldegrave (1930-1979), reflect their dedication to the project, as well as to the editor. Likewise, the nine folders of correspondence between Lewis and his associate and co-author Allen T. Hazen show their mutual dedication to Horace Walpole between 1934 and 1977.
  While the letters in the subseries are chiefly addressed to Wilmarth Lewis, many of a more personal nature were sent to the Lewises as a couple. Several sets of friends, including Dean and Alice Acheson, Stanhope and Nannie Bayne-Jones, Reg and Hope Coombe, Richard and Jo Kimball, Archibald and Ada MacLeish, Edgar and Constance Richardson, S. Dillon and Mary Ripley, and Arnold and Janetta Whitridge, are represented in the files, and there are occasional draft replies to them from Annie Burr Lewis. Other friends such as Leonard Bacon, brothers Moreau and William Adams Delano and their sister Susan Delano McKelvey, Felix Frankfurter, and Thornton Wilder and his sister Isabel wrote the Lewises, as did English friends Sydney and Marjorie Roberts, and Lucy Rosamond Bentley, who continued her correspondence with the Lewises for nearly thirty years after the death of her husband Richard in 1936. Also filed here are letters from Annie Lewis's family writing to Wilmarth Lewis after her death: members of the Auchincloss, Biltz, Jennings, Nash, Rutherfurd, and other families, as well as Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis; letters from Wilmarth Lewis's family are in their own subseries.
  The files too contain fan mail received by Lewis, and none are more expressive than the letters from Marilynne K. Roach and Eric M. Simon. Both wrote introductory letters to Lewis, with Roach's first note opening "This is something in the nature of a fan-letter & thank-you note..." for introducing her, through his Mellon lecture series, to Horace Walpole. A children's book author and illustrator, Roach delighted Lewis each Christmas from 1970 to 1978 by sending him a Christmas card with an original watercolor drawing of Horace Walpole engaged in his daily activities; Lewis put all the cards on display in the library every December. Simon was a graphic designer, calligrapher, and painter self-styled as "Simon de Pittsfield" when he was in that Massachusetts city working for the Eaton Paper Company, or "St. Simon de Rego Park" when writing from his home in the Queens borough of New York City. Simon learned of Lewis on reading Geoffrey T. Hellman's two profiles, "The Steward of Strawberry Hill," in the August 1949 issues of The New Yorker, and immediately penned a letter of admiration in his curious eighteenth-century manner. After inviting himself to visit Lewis and his collection in Farmington, and arriving on June 23, 1950, Simon sent a decorated thank-you note/remembrance featuring portraits of Horace Walpole, Madame du Deffand, and himself, among others, with a rose painted especially for Mrs. Lewis.
  The subseries Chapman-Lewis-Whibley Correspondence, Lewis Family Correspondence, Responses to Publications, and Tributes and Condolences, are special groups of letters that had been kept separate from the run of General Correspondence, and are further described at their subseries levels.
  - General Correspondence
    - Aa-Az, general (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - A. N. Marquis & Company, 1952–1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Abbott, Edith McKeon, 1968–1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Abbott and Holder (Gallery), 1963–1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Acheson, Alice, 1954–1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Acheson, David, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971, 1938–1956 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971, 1957–1974 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Acorn Club of Connecticut, 1946–1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Adams, C. Kingsley (Charles Kingsley), 1899-, 1935–1975 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
    - Adams, Frederick B. (Frederick Baldwin), 1910-2001, 1937–1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951, 1937–1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Adee, George T., 1939–1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Adler, Regina, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Alameda County Historical Society, 1960–1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Alan G. Thomas (Firm), 1948–1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Alcorn, Paul, 1937–1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - All Souls College (University of Oxford), 1971–1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Allen, Elizabeth S., 1952–1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Allen, Lafon, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Allen, Reginald, 1955–1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Allen, W. Herbert, 1946–1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Allentuck, Marcia, 1928-, 1957–1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Allison, John Maudgridge Snowden, 1888-1944, 1938–1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Alsop, John DeKevon, 1953–1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Alsop, Joseph, 1910-1989, 1935–1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Alsop, Stewart, 1957–1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Alsop, Susan Mary, 1961–1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Altschul, Frank, 1887-1981, 1930–1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Amberg, Anthony, 1936-, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1954–1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1942–1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - American Art Galleries, 1925–1926 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - American Book Company, 1933–1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - American Heritage Publishing Company, 1958–1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - American Kennel Club, 1939–1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - American Law Institute, 1962–1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - American Library Association, 1948–1961 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - American Museum in Britain, 1961–1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1941–1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Amherst College, 1951–1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Anderson, Jerome E., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Andrews, Wayne, 1946–1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Anthony, Helen Virginia, and Nellie Virginia, 1922–1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Anthony W. Laywood (Firm), 1969–1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Antiquarian & Landmarks Society, Inc. of Connecticut, 1950–1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Antiques Magazine, 1953–1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Archibald, Raymond Clare, 1875-1955, 1940–1952 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Argyll, Niall Diarmid Campbell, Duke of, 1872-1949, 1924–1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Arizona Pioneers' Historical Society, 1960–1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Armour, Lester, 1936–1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Armstrong, Barbara, 1961–1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Armstrong, Ronald, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1935–1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1935–1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Art Institute of Chicago. Ryerson Library, 1966–1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Arthur Rau (Firm), 1933–1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Arthur Tooth & Sons, 1950–1954 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Ashburn, Frank Davis, 1903-, 1948–1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Ashmolean Museum, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Asprey & Co., 1974–1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Asscher, Martin, 1937–1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Athenæum Club (London, England), 1965–1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Atherton, Herbert M., 1963–1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Atherton, John, 1953–1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Atherton, Ray, 1883-1960, and Maude, 1943–1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Auchincloss family, 1940–1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Auchincloss, Hugh D., 1937–1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Auchincloss, Hugh D., Jr., and Alice Lyon, 1949–1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Auchincloss, Janet Lee, 1907-1989, 1947–1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Auchincloss, Louis, 1954–1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Aymar, Gordon C. (Gordon Christian), 1893-1989, 1956–1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Ba-Bri, general (Box 7, Folder 3-7)
    - Bro-Bz, general (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - B. F. Stevens & Brown, Ltd., 1932–1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - B. H. Blackwell Ltd., 1938–1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - B. Weinreb Architectural Books Ltd., 1956–1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), 1899-1968, and Margaret, 1937–1970 (Box 8, Folder 6-9)
    - Babbidge, Homer D., 1969–1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1887-1954, 1924–1956 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
    - Baily, Harold J., 1955–1961 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Baird, Thomas, 1923-1990, 1977–1979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Baker, C. H. Collins (Charles Henry Collins), 1880-1959, 1939–1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Baker, Liva, 1968–1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Baker, Margie, 1974–1975 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Baker, Mark, 1952-, 1970–1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Baker, W. J., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Baldridge, H. M. and Jean, 1954–1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin, Henry De Forest, 1934–1937 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Ballard, Patrick L., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Ballinger, Marnie, 1959–1965 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Bantlett, George, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Bard, Philip, 1898-1977, 1966–1977 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Bare, Carl B., 1954–1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Baring Brothers & Co. Ltd., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Barker, John, 1934-, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Barker, Kathleen, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Barker, Priscilla Curtis, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Barlow, Jeffrey G., 1946-, 1978–1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Barnard, T. T., 1962–1963 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Barnes, John Hampton, 1949–1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Barnes, John Hampton, Jr., 1970–1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Barney, Philip C. and Austin D., 1954–1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Barney, Laura D., 1925–1940 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Barnhart, Clarence L. (Clarence Lewis), 1900-1993, 1950–1953 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Barrell, Rex A., 1972–1978 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller, 1901-1991, 1956–1977 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Barrett, Oliver R. (Oliver Roger), 1873-1950, 1934–1938 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Bate, Fred B., 1925 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Bates, Richard, 1967–1969 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bates, R.W., 1949–1966 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Bateson, Frederick Wilse, 1901-1978, 1930–1944 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Bausch, Carl P., 1973–1978 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, 1938–1939 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970, and Nannie Moore, 1940–1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Bayntun, George, 1873-1940, 1923–1940 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Beam, Fay, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Beard, Geoffrey, 1929-, 1950–1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Beazley, A. Stuart, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956, 1954–1956 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Behrman, S. N. (Samuel Nathaniel), 1893-1973, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John), 1886-1970, 1951–1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Beirne, Francis F., 1890-, and Rosamund, 1952–1969 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Belanger, Terry, 1970–1977 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Bell, Elizabeth, 1949–1962 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Bell, John, 1962–1969 (Box 11, Folder 12)